

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





Praveen Raju Praveen Raju (Featured) Certified PMP & Certified Scrum Master, Having 15 years of exposure in maintenance, development, support of web application in java, j2ee technologies accross the Reatail, HealthCare, Manufacturing domains with the versatile role of Technical Lead Total Experience: 15 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Technical Lead Current Company: Suhail Bahwan Group (Holding) LLC Notice Period: 1 Month Current Location: Muscat **Highest Degree:** Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, United Arab Emirates (UAE), United Kingdom (UK) Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance Role: Project Mgr-IT/Software Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Married Key Skills: Technical Lead, Project Manager-IT/Software, Application Development, Application Support, Application -Maintenance, Application Design, Requirement Gathering, Requirement Analysis, Coding, Testing, Debugging, Client Management, Java, J2EE, MVC, PMP, Scrum Waster Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Jump to Section

Last Active: 21-Jan-21

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects | Work Authorization

Summary

PMP, Certified Scrum Master,15 years of IT experience in analysis, design, development, documentation, implementing and testing of software systems in Java, J2EE and Internet technologies.

Strong Knowledge on Application Development using Software Development Life Cycle SDLC using various methodologies like Agile/Scrum, Waterfall,

Strong experience in Spring Framework such as Spring Boot, M/C, IOC, AOP and Spring JDBC AJAX, Restful WEB SERVICES, Hibernate

Experience in using build/deploy tools such as Jenkins, Dockers for Continuous Integration & Deployment for Mcroservices. Experience with Use-Case design, Class and Sequence diagrams using UML

Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Experience in implementing Java EE design patterns such as M/C, Singleton, Session Facade, DAO, DTO, and Business Delegate in the development of Multi-Tier distributed Enterprise Applications.

Career exposure in HRMS, Healthcare, Manufacturing, Retail domains,

Work Experience

Suhail Bahwan Group (Holding) LLC as Technical Lead

Oct 2016 to Till Date

Oct' 16 - Till now HRMS Project:

Client Suhail Bahwan Group Holding LLC

Java 8, Ext JS, Spring boot, Angular JS, Hibernate, SQL server 2012, Eclipse Rally & Maven tool, **Environment:**

Scrum Master, Team Lead, Senior Developer Role:

Brief description of the project:

HRMS - Human resource management system. Aimed to provide web based HR management tool for all types of divisions. This project includes employee personal and professional details tracking system, providing soft skills related training center for all employees, working with technical team to recruit fresher's and technical professionals in to the projects, Tracking the software project related management and provide best output to the customers

It's a collection of business objects pertaining to Human Resource Management. The HRMS Module consists of Objects such as Employee, Benefits, Deductions, Training, Attendance, Payroll, Loans, Appraisal, Payroll, Leave, Passport, Salary, Travel, Accommodation, Allowance, and Credit purchase, Furniture, Manpower, Settlement, Telephone, Vehicle and Advances etc.

Responsible for:

Facilitate Daily Scrum, Sprint Planning, Sprint demo & sprint retro meetings

Coordinate and work with team and business stakeholders for project planning and execution.

Involved in requirement gathering analysis and design phase of the project. of the project Implemented REST Microservices using spring boot

- Facilitate Daily Scrum, Sprint Planning, Sprint demo & sprint retro meetings
- ordinate and work with team and husiness stakeholders for project planning and execution

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

- oooramate and work with team and business statements for project planning and chooses.
- * Involved in requirement gathering analysis and Coding on modules ,design phase of the project
- Perform build, release management & configuration management activities
- * Implemented using Spring IO/ Spring Boot and Hibernate ORM Implemented Java EE components using Spring IMC, Spring IOC, spring transactions and spring security modules

Capgemini Consulting as Team Lead

Jan 2012 to Sep 2016

Sep'14 - Jan'15

Project: Olympus Web Application

Client GE Healthcare

Environment: Java 1.7, Spring, Hibernate, Rest web services, oracle 10g, Eclipse Rally & Maven tool, Agile

Methodologies.

Role: Team Lead, Agile Development Team

Brief description of the project:

Olympus web application used by Lab assistance, admin to collect the patient details such as disease information, samples information, profile information's. Processing, Providing Reports back to the patients by considering this as an order

Responsible for:

- * Requirement gathering and task allocation.
- * Implemented service layer classes using Spring IOC and AOP classes.
- * Prepared Database Design & requirement plan.
- * Coding on modules related to Order & user modules
- * Participate in code reviews & Fix code defects in modules
- Code review and deployment.
- * Development of new listeners for producers and consumer for Rabbit MQ.
- * Team management and mentoring.
- Used Spring JDBC and Hibernate DAO layers to offer abstraction for the business from the database related code (CRUD).
- Development to expose User Profile services to other departments users using RESTful WS.

Feb'12 - Oct'14

Project: Asset Management System

Client GE Healthcare

Environment: Java 1.7, Struts 1.oracle 10g, Eclipse Rally & Maven tool, Agile Methodologies.

Role: Team Lead, Developer

Brief description of the project:

iCenter is web based application of Enterprise Asset management, iCenter is used to manage different kind of asset. Broadly there are two different kind of asset, BIO med and DI, icenter is for managing DI asset. There could be two different kind of user of icenter application, 1st is Internal that is GE employee and other is External that is individual Hospital or facility who has taken equipment or device from GE or has taken some kind of service like extended contract from GE. By using icenter application, managing asset, asset can be of GE or non GE. If some hospital has taken new equipment from GE then it has some contract associated with equipment. For non GE asset then hospital can go any new contract with GE.

iCenter application helps to management in order to take business decision. Management can take different kind of report like average asset utilization period, average asset up time or asset down time, they can also generate report of how many service request within specified period of time, they can also see the report how many contract is going to end in coming month so they can again approach to with new business.

Responsible for:

Code review and deployment.

Involved in creation of technical design documents.

Team management and mentoring.

Requirement gathering and task allocation.

Customer interaction and status update and planning.

Infosys Limited as Developer

Mar 2010 to Dec 2011

Mar'10 - Mar'11

Project: Sync Server Engine

Client Apple

Environment: Mac OS/Windows XP/9x, Java 1.5.berkely DB

Role: Developer

Brief description of the project:

This Project is all about enhancement of a sync server application. Issues of the customers are recorded as RADAR. Replicating the radar issue, analyzing the user data, by manual and testing tool, then providing the solution to the issue by enhancing the sync server application. Application is developed using java technology with BD database.

Responsible for:

- * Assigning, monitoring Task with subordinates.
- * Fixing the radar issue.
- * Testing (Clog/DB Tool Testing) Device Testing (iPhone 4.1)
- * Developed the Presentation and Controller layers using JSP, HTML, Java Script, Business logic using Spring IOC,

AOP, DTO, JTA, and Persistent layer DAO, Hibernate for all modules

- * Prepared SRS document
- Designing and Implemented the Microflows.
- * Testing using the FitPRO Tool.

^ Back to Top

Education

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: **Certified Scrum Master** Azure fundamentals

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Java 5/6/7.0/8	2019
OOAD , UML (Visio, Star UML) & J2EE	2019
My SQL ,SQL Server 2000/2005	2019
Oracle 9i/10g	2017
J2EE	2019
JSP, Servlet, jpa, Hibernate	2017
HTML, XML, Ext Js	2019
JavaScript, web services, AJAX,	2019
Weblogic, JBOSS, Apache Tomcat	2019
WINDOWS 98/2000/XP	2019
Eclipse, Visio, Star UML	2019
VSS, SVN	2019
Eclipse, NetBeans	2019

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Telugu	Proficient			✓
Kannada	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: HRMS

Client: Suhail Bahwan Group LLC Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Muscat, Oman Role: Project Leader

Duration: Oct 2016 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 6

Skill Used: Java 8, Ext JS, Restful web Services (JERSEY, Spring Boot), Hibernate, SQL server 2012, Edipse Rally & Maven tool, Tomcat 7, Jenkins

Implemented REST Microservices using spring boot

- Facilitate Daily Scrum, Sprint Planning, Sprint demo & sprint retro meetings
- Coordinate and work with team and business stakeholders for project planning and execution.
- Involved in requirement

Project Details: HRMS Human resource management system. Aimed to provide web based HR management tool for all types of divisions. This project includes employee personal and professional details tracking system, providing soft skills related training center for all employees, working with technical team to recruit freshers and technical professionals in to the projects, Tracking the software project related management and provide best output to the customers

Its a collection of business objects pertaining to Human Resource Management. The HRMS Module consists of Objects such as Employee, Benefits, Deductions, Training, Attendance, Payroll, Loans, Appraisal, Payroll, Leave, Passport, Salary, Travel, Accommodation, Allowance, and Credit purchase, Furniture, Manpower, Settlement, Telephone, Vehicle and Advances etc.

Project Title: Kermit Web Application Client: GE Health Care

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2005 - Jun 2007 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 12

Skill Used: Java 1.7, Spring, Angular JS, Hibernate, Rest web services, SQL server 2012, Eclipse Rally & Maven tool, Agile Methodologies. Rabbit MQ, HL7 Service

Role Description: * Requirement gathering and task allocation.

- Implemented service layer classes using Spring IOC and AOP classes.
- Prepared Database Design & requirement plan.
- Coding on modules related to Order & user modules
- Participate in code reviews & Fix

Project Details: This project deals with management of automobile purchase system. It implements time and cost saving measures to increase business profitability. It stores the manufacturer and purchase order information in a database. This project automates the process of selecting manufacturers and generating purchase orders. To secure the process of generating purchase order, role based access has been implemented for employees generating the purchase order.

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Countries: Oman

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.